# Samuel Olaniyan

403-888-1568 | Samuel.FMichaels@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/samuel-olaniyan/

# **Professional Summary**

Driven full-stack software developer with 3 years of experience and a unique blend of technical and financial expertise, leveraging diverse programming languages and tools to deliver efficient, and reliable solutions. Demonstrates exceptional problem-solving skills, while also collaborating with web designers to develop and implement business systems and software that enhance productivity.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages: C#, JavaScript, Python, Java.
- Front-end: ReactJS, Tailwind, Bootstrap
- Back-end: .Net, NodeJS, Django, Flask.
- Design: Figma, A/B testing, UX Research
- Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.
- Cloud: AWS
- Other tools: Git, GitHub, Docker, Jira

### **Soft Skills**

- Communication (Oral and Written)
- Organization and Time management
- Team-player
- Self-starter
- Detail-oriented
- Adaptable

# **Work Experience**

## Scottish Water, Aberdeen, United Kingdom

### **Enterprise Architect**

May 2022 - Aug 2022

- Developed a vendor-applications lifecycle gap management framework, resulting in a 30% reduction in business disruptions, a 25% improvement in software asset updates, and 15% cost savings.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and develop 3+ scalable and flexible systems, increasing business efficiency by 35% and streamlining internal processes.
- Conducted business requirements research for 3 projects and evaluated the impact of solutions on the overall system to achieve a better synergy between IT and the business.

# Access Bank PLC, Lagos, Nigeria

#### **Software Developer**

Jan 2019 – Nov 2021

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop, and implement 5+ web-based applications, automating over 100 processes, resulting in a 40% decrease in process turn-around time across the organization.
- Designed and maintained databases, ensuring 99% data consistency with zero recorded cases of data breaches.
- Assessed the technical feasibility of UI designs for 5+ projects, ensuring final output alignment with the organization's branding and maintaining consistent product quality across all applications.
- Implemented DevOps practices, reducing deployment and testing time by 40% and enhancing the overall software development lifecycle.
- Actively participated in debugging, creating user documentation, and code reviews for 5+ projects, contributing to a significant improvement in code quality and reducing bug occurrences by 20%.

Treasury Analyst Apr 2017 – Jan 2019

 Monitored and analyzed the company's cash flow, identifying opportunities for improvement and implementing solutions to optimize cash management.

- Developed and maintained strong relationships with banks and financial institutions, negotiating favourable terms for loans and other financial instruments.
- Conducted detailed financial analysis to support decision-making and strategic planning.
- Led a team of five that contributed more than 20% to the organization's revenue in 2021 (the highest single contribution by any team).

#### **Education**

### **MSc. Information Technology**

University of Aberdeen, United Kingdom

Jan 2022 - Mar 2023

### **BSc.** Chemical Engineering

University of Ilorin, Nigeria

Nov 2010 - Aug 2015

# **Projects**

- Process Maker Software (Access Bank PLC Lagos, Nigeria)
  Collaborated with a team to automate over 100 processes across different divisions in the bank. This project was implemented using ReactJS, NodeJS and PostgreSQL database.
- Child-Adult Relationship Observation Tool (University of Aberdeen)
  Led the development of video-coding software for Mellow Parenting, an NGO focused on improving child-parent relationships. The software enables researchers to observe and code interactions between mothers and their young children. Developed the application using the MERN stack, which includes MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js.
- Personal projects
   Available at <a href="https://www.samuelolaniyan.tech/">https://www.samuelolaniyan.tech/</a>

### **Certifications**

Microsoft Power Platform Fundamentals (PL-900)	Jul 2022
Professional Scrum Master (PSM1), Scrum.Org	Jan 2022
Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner, IBM	Jul 2020